Guide to the United States Railroad Securities Commission Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
United States Railroad Securities Commission papers
1890-1914
MS 517
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
(4 boxes)
Correspondence, testimony, legal briefs, published reports and studies, and other papers used by William E.S. Griswold, secretary of the Railroad Securities Commission, for an investigation of the railroads' issuance of stocks and bonds, 1910-1911. Includes "Proceedings of the investigation" (3 vols.). Correspondents include Louis D. Brandeis, Charles G. Dawes, Stuyvesant Fish, James Jerome Hill, Walker Downer Hines, Robert Scott Lovett, Samuel Rea, Jacob Henry Schiff, Paul Moritz Warburg, and George Woodward Wickersham.
United States. Railroad Securities Commission
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William Edward Schenck Griswold, 1920 and William E. S. Griswold, Jr., 1967.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The U.S. Railroad Securities Commission Papers extend from 1890 to 1914, although the bulk of the material falls within the two years, 1910 and 1911.
The collection deals with the investigation, in 1910, of questions pertaining to the issuance of stocks and bonds by railroad corporations. Included in the material is the correspondence of the Commision, assorted documents collected for its use, and the bound testimony of its public hearings.
The collection consists of 4 containers, holding approximately 2000 items, and three bound volumes.
Other Finding Aids
Additional information not yet available in the online version of the finding aid exists in the repository. Contact Manuscripts and Archives for assistance.
Business; Industrial development bonds; Railroads -- Finance; Tender offers (Securities); Griswold, William Edward Schenck, 1872-1964; Schiff, Jacob H. (Jacob Henry), 1847-1920; Warburg, Paul M. (Paul Moritz), 1868-1932; Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936; United States. Railroad Securities Commission
- Inventory
  - Correspondence, 1910 March 14-1911 March 1 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1911 March 2-1914 December (Box 2)
  - Proceedings of Investigation (3 volumes), 1910-1911 (Box 2)
  - U.S. Congress, Acts and Bills regarding Railroads, 1890-1910 (Box 3)
  - Investigations of Interstate Commerce Commission regarding Railroads, 1890-1910 (Box 3)
  - Bibliographical Information used by Commision (Box 3)
  - Correspondence
    - Letters to Railroad Securities Commission, 1911 (Box 3)
    - Bound volume of letters, 1910 February 25-1911 October 17 (Box 3)
    - Some published reports bound with letters (Box 3)
      General
      Correspondents list available in repository. Contact MSSA for assistance.
  - Manuscripts
    - "Constitutional and Statutory Provisions of the several states and territories and of Canada in regard to Securities of Railroad Corporations". Typed MS., bound. (Box 3)
    - U.S. Railroad Securities Commission. Information concerning preferred stock of leading railroads". Typed MS (34 pp.), 1911 (Box 3)
    - "Listing of State, P[ublic] S[ervice] Commissions and Capitalization". Holograph and Typed MS., bound (15 pp.) (Box 3)
    - "Compilation of court cases, citing abstracts of court decisions, extracts and statements of people used by Securities Commission". Typed MS (157 pp.) (Box 3)
  - Published material
    - Reference to State Laws in regard to Securities of Railroad Corporations. Annotated working copy (52 pp.) [2 copies], 1911 (Box 3)
  - Printed Material regarding State Railroad Laws (Box 4)
  - Speeches and Writings re Railroad Capitalization and Federal Regulation. (Box 4)
    Index available in repository. Contact MSSA for assistance.
  - Miscellaneous Data used by Commission, 1905-1910 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Charts regarding Railroad Revenues and Securities (Box 4)